<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Seth dot cool</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Seth dot cool</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Height and NCAA Hoops</title>
      <link>/2017/12/21/height-and-ncaa-hoops/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/12/21/height-and-ncaa-hoops/</guid>
      <description>I’m hellbent on winning a March Madness pool this year, and have been reading up on modern basketball analytics (i.e., KenPom, Dean Oliver, Sagarin, Lopez).
In the process, I’ve played around with scraping data from various websites, to analyze in R.
This is a quick exploration of player height according to 2017-18 NCAA D-I Men’s Basketball Rosters.
Average Height by TeamD-I teams tend to be around 6&#39;5&amp;quot; in average height – 8 inches taller than the average US adult male at 5&#39;9&amp;quot;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s the plural of Eephus?</title>
      <link>/2017/11/11/whats-the-plural-of-eephus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/11/11/whats-the-plural-of-eephus/</guid>
      <description>I downloaded a fairly large amount of pitch data from the MLB Statcast database: every pitch thrown during the 2017 season, with ~75 variables about each.
What’s the plural of Eephus?For the uninitiated, the Eephus pitch is a very, very slow baseball pitch. I’d hoped that the plural of eephus would be eephucies (like matrices), but it turns out isn’t a real word at all. As far as I can tell from the Google Ngram viewer, it was first used in a baseball context around 1960.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2017 MLB Team Exploration: Mostly Injuries</title>
      <link>/2017/11/01/2017-mlb-team-exploration-mostly-injuries/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/11/01/2017-mlb-team-exploration-mostly-injuries/</guid>
      <description>Although the Washington Nationals have crashed out of the MLB playoffs for the fourth time in four appearances since 2012, I’m not ready to put the 2017 season to bed. I downloaded acouple of datasets from the 2017 MLB Regular Season to play around with while practicing exploratory data analysis and To practice exploratory data analysis plotting with ggplot2:
Team Batting (baseball reference)Team Pitching (baseball reference)Team Disabled List data (spotrac)I have a pretty superficial understanding of modern sabermetrics (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Washington, D.C. Service Requests (2016)</title>
      <link>/2017/10/27/exploring-washington-d.c.-service-requests-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/10/27/exploring-washington-d.c.-service-requests-2016/</guid>
      <description>I’ve lived in Washington for about four years, but have lived in the D.C. metropolitan area my whole life. When looking for datasets to practice ggplot2 plotting, I came across Open Data DC, a catalog of datasets maintained by various city government agencies.
I gravitated toward the Newly Updated or Added section, hoping to find a data that I haven’t read much about before. I decided on Service Request Data (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to the least-cool dot-cool on the Internet</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>I registered the seth.cool domain a couple of years ago with no project in mind – only the misguided assumptions that (1) someone else would buy it, and (2) that I am cool. I’ve decided to finally use my first-mover’s advantage to share data-related projects as I work on them.
A brief background on that: As my job has evolved to include more and more data analysis, I’ve found myself spending a lot of time waiting for Excel to unfreeze respond.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to the least-cool dot-cool on the Internet</title>
      <link>/2017/10/23/welcome-to-the-least-cool-dot-cool-on-the-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/10/23/welcome-to-the-least-cool-dot-cool-on-the-internet/</guid>
      <description>I registered the seth.cool domain a couple of years ago with no project in mind – only the misguided assumptions that (1) someone else would buy it, and (2) that I am cool. I’ve decided to finally use my first-mover’s advantage to share data-related projects as I work on them.
A brief background on that: As my job has evolved to include more and more data analysis, I’ve found myself spending a lot of time waiting for Excel to unfreeze respond.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>