<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Seth dot cool</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Seth dot cool</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Using an API to get College Football Data</title>
      <link>/2019/08/17/using-an-api-to-get-college-football-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/08/17/using-an-api-to-get-college-football-data/</guid>
      <description>As I’ve started to interact with more web data at work, I’ve felt the need to get more familiar with third-party APIs. Since the college football season kicks off next weekend, I’m writing this post as I experiment with the (seemingly) simple CollegeFootballData.com API for the first time.
The CollegeFootballData.com website has a nice interface for running reports on teams, games, drives, plays, recruiting, and more. However, some of these datasets, like plays, are very granular, which means that pulling out a full season’s worth of plays would require exporting one week of data at a time, and mashing them together in another tool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three-pointers after offensive rebounds</title>
      <link>/2018/12/30/is-the-best-time-to-shoot-a-three-pointer-after-an-offensive-rebound/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/12/30/is-the-best-time-to-shoot-a-three-pointer-after-an-offensive-rebound/</guid>
      <description>During the Duke-Kentucky college basketball season opener, after one of twelve of Duke’s made three-point shots, Jay Bilas claimed that “the best time to shoot a three is following an offensive rebound.” I’ve heard other commentators say this before, and wondered if it’s actually true. This post walks through my investigation of that claim using play-by-play data from the 2017-18 men’s college basketball season.
Preparing the dataMy play-by-play dataset includes 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using market valuations in an NFL Pick&#39;em Pool</title>
      <link>/2018/09/20/using-market-valuations-in-an-nfl-pick-em-pool/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/09/20/using-market-valuations-in-an-nfl-pick-em-pool/</guid>
      <description>This Fall, I’m playing in an NFL Pick’em contest with some friends from college. Each week, I predict the outcome of every NFL game according to Yahoo’s point-spread. For example, during Week 1 when the Patriots hosted the Texans, Yahoo assigned the Texans a seven-point handicap. My prediction came down to whether the Patriots would beat the Texans by more than seven points, or whether I thought the Texans would lose by no more than seven points (or win outright).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parking Violations in DC</title>
      <link>/2018/06/29/parking-violations-in-dc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/06/29/parking-violations-in-dc/</guid>
      <description>I have very few complaints about living in Washington, D.C., but if I were forced to pick one, it’d be searching for on-street parking. When I found the several public Parking Violations on Open Data DC, I figured I might be able to extract some insights into the best (and worst) blocks to look for a spot during high-demand times.
My original intent was to try to model the parking violations to identify the optimal times and locations of available parking spots near my house.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing the NCAA Men&#39;s Basketball Tournament Field of 68</title>
      <link>/2018/03/20/analyzing-the-ncaa-men-s-basketball-tournament-field-of-68/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/03/20/analyzing-the-ncaa-men-s-basketball-tournament-field-of-68/</guid>
      <description>I just returned from an event in Las Vegas, which intentionally coincided with the first weekend of the NCAA Men’s Basketball Tournament. In preparation, I attempted to analyze the 68 tournament NCAA Tournament teams, hoping to make a few profitable predictions. I went in with low expectations, thanks in part to statistics posts about how difficult it is to profit, even with better-than-the-bookmaker’s odds.
I ended up breaking even. Here are a few of the plots I created using data from two Ken’s: Pomeroy’s Kenpom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Height and NCAA Hoops</title>
      <link>/2017/12/21/height-and-ncaa-hoops/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/12/21/height-and-ncaa-hoops/</guid>
      <description>I’m hellbent on winning a March Madness pool this year, and have been reading up on modern basketball analytics (i.e., KenPom, Dean Oliver, Sagarin, Lopez).
In the process, I’ve played around with scraping data from various websites, to analyze in R.
This is a quick exploration of player height according to 2017-18 NCAA D-I Men’s Basketball Rosters.
Average Height by TeamD-I teams tend to be around 6&#39;5&amp;quot; in average height – 8 inches taller than the average US adult male at 5&#39;9&amp;quot;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s the plural of Eephus?</title>
      <link>/2017/11/11/whats-the-plural-of-eephus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/11/11/whats-the-plural-of-eephus/</guid>
      <description>I downloaded a fairly large amount of pitch data from the MLB Statcast database: every pitch thrown during the 2017 season, with ~75 variables about each.
What’s the plural of Eephus?For the uninitiated, the Eephus pitch is a very, very slow baseball pitch. I’d hoped that the plural of eephus would be eephucies (like matrices), but it turns out isn’t a real word at all. As far as I can tell from the Google Ngram viewer, it was first used in a baseball context around 1960.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2017 MLB Team Exploration: Mostly Injuries</title>
      <link>/2017/11/01/2017-mlb-team-exploration-mostly-injuries/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/11/01/2017-mlb-team-exploration-mostly-injuries/</guid>
      <description>Although the Washington Nationals have crashed out of the MLB playoffs for the fourth time in four appearances since 2012, I’m not ready to put the 2017 season to bed. I downloaded acouple of datasets from the 2017 MLB Regular Season to play around with while practicing exploratory data analysis and To practice exploratory data analysis plotting with ggplot2:
Team Batting (baseball reference)Team Pitching (baseball reference)Team Disabled List data (spotrac)I have a pretty superficial understanding of modern sabermetrics (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Washington, D.C. Service Requests (2016)</title>
      <link>/2017/10/27/exploring-washington-d.c.-service-requests-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/10/27/exploring-washington-d.c.-service-requests-2016/</guid>
      <description>I’ve lived in Washington for about four years, but have lived in the D.C. metropolitan area my whole life. When looking for datasets to practice ggplot2 plotting, I came across Open Data DC, a catalog of datasets maintained by various city government agencies.
I gravitated toward the Newly Updated or Added section, hoping to find a data that I haven’t read much about before. I decided on Service Request Data (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to the least-cool dot-cool on the Internet</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>I registered the seth.cool domain a couple of years ago with no project in mind – only the misguided assumptions that (1) someone else would buy it, and (2) that I am cool. I’ve decided to finally use my first-mover’s advantage to share data-related projects as I work on them.
Data analysis is a relatively new interest of mine. I started learning R after complaining to a friend about how much time I spend waiting for Excel to unfreeze at work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to the least-cool dot-cool on the Internet</title>
      <link>/2017/10/23/welcome-to-the-least-cool-dot-cool-on-the-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/10/23/welcome-to-the-least-cool-dot-cool-on-the-internet/</guid>
      <description>I registered the seth.cool domain a couple of years ago with no project in mind – only the misguided assumptions that (1) someone else would buy it, and (2) that I am cool. I’ve decided to finally use my first-mover’s advantage to share data-related projects as I work on them.
Data analysis is a relatively new interest of mine. I started learning R after complaining to a friend about how much time I spend waiting for Excel to unfreeze at work.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>