<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rstats on Seth dot cool</title>
    <link>/categories/rstats/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rstats on Seth dot cool</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/rstats/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Product Analytics on My Own Spotify Usage</title>
      <link>/2020/08/26/exploring-my-own-spotify-usage/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/08/26/exploring-my-own-spotify-usage/</guid>
      <description>Spotify does an incredible job of personalizing the user experience, using machine learning to curate daily playlists based on past listening habits, and surfacing new music recommendations via the Your Discover Weekly.
Spotify’s CEO recently noted on an earnings call that their secret sauce is online experimentation – running tests on its ~300M users, and using the learnings to improve its products. Two of the ways that Spotify evaluates the effectiveness of their experiments are (1) measuring increased engagement (streaming for longer periods of time), and (2) increased user retention (users returning to use Spotify’s products in the future).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing Gunshot Detection Data in DC</title>
      <link>/2019/12/30/analyzing-gunshot-detection-data-in-dc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/12/30/analyzing-gunshot-detection-data-in-dc/</guid>
      <description>Washington, D.C. uses a system called SpotShotter, which involves acoustic sensors that can detect the presence and location of gunshots. The devices, which I believe are usually attached to utility poles, also transmit alerts to law enforcement, who can then respond to the incident. The city also makes the data publicly available on a quarterly basis via Open Data DC.
This is an incredibly sad topic, as the data here is mostly generated by real acts of violence throughout the city.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>